Guide to the Robert Mearns Yerkes Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Professional Correspondence, 1898-1982; Series I; 22.25 linear feet (54 boxes)
  - Marple, Lucius E. (*), 1898-1967 (Box 33, Folder 625-629)
  - Marquis, Donald G. (*), 1934-1950 (Box 33, Folder 630)
    See also: box 105, folders 1976-1978
  - Marshall, James, 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 631)
  - Martin, Lillien J. (*), 1917-1945 (Box 33, Folder 632)
  - Maslow, A.H. (*), 1932-1945 (Box 33, Folder 633)
  - Mason, Max (*), 1931-1943 (Box 33, Folder 634)
  - Mast, S.O. (*), 1909-1936 (Box 33, Folder 635)
  - Mateer, Florence (*), 1915-1916 (Box 33, Folder 636)
  - Mather, Kirtley S.
    See: box 55, folders 1048-1049
  - May, Mark A. (*), 1932-1951 (Box 33, Folder 637)
    See also: box 104, folders 1957-1958
  - Mayer, Alfred G., 1905-1914 (Box 33, Folder 638)
  - Mendel, Lafayette B., 1925-1935 (Box 34, Folder 639)
  - Menninger, Karl A., 1934-1944 (Box 34, Folder 640)
  - Menninger, William C. (Box 34, Folder 640)
  - Meriam, Junius L. (*), 1903-1957 (Box 34, Folder 641-643)
  - Merriam, Charles E. (*), 1923-1942 (Box 34, Folder 644)
    See also: box 88, folders 1695-1696
  - Merriam, John C. (*), 1916-1943 (Box 34, Folder 645-648)
    See also: box 58, folders 1109-1110 box 60, folders 1142-1144 box 106, folders 2003-2004
  - Meyer, Adolph (*), 1909-1940 (Box 34, Folder 649)
  - Meyerson, I., 1927-1948 (Box 34, Folder 650)
  - Miles, Rufus E. (*), 1903-1957, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 651)
  - Miles, Walter R. (*), 1914-1963 (Box 34, Folder 652-653)
    See also: box 71, folders 1368-1371 box 105, folders 1971
  - Miller, Gerrit S., Jr. (*), 1928-1940 (Box 34, Folder 654)
  - Miller, Herbert A. (*), 1905-1941 (Box 35, Folder 655)
  - Miller, Neal E., 1948-1955 (Box 35, Folder 656)
  - Milne, Lorus J. (*), 1946-1948 (Box 35, Folder 657)
  - Minot, Charles S., 1908-1914 (Box 35, Folder 658)
  - Mize, Robert H. (*), 1932-1933 (Box 35, Folder 659)
  - Moe, Henry A., 1945, 1953 (Box 35, Folder 660)
  - Montagu, M.F. Ashley (*), 1938-1953 (Box 35, Folder 661)
  - Moore, Carl R. (*), 1937-1955 (Box 35, Folder 662)
  - Moore, Henry T. (*), 1916-1941 (Box 35, Folder 663)
    See also: box 70, folders 1347-1349
  - Morford, Helen S. (*), 1924-1979, undated (Box 35, Folder 664-666)
    See also: box 111-112, folders 2079-2092
  - Morgan, Arthur E. (*), 1945-1951 (Box 35, Folder 667)
  - Morgan, C. Lloyd (*), 1904-1936 (Box 35, Folder 668)
  - Morgan, T.H. (*), 1904-1949 (Box 35, Folder 669)
  - Morgulis, Sergius (*), 1911-1914 (Box 35, Folder 670)
  - Morison, Robert S., 1953 (Box 35, Folder 671)
  - Morris, Charles G., 1944-1949 (Box 35, Folder 672)
  - Morrow, Dwight, 1930-1946 (Box 35, Folder 673)
  - Morrow, Elizabeth C. (Box 35, Folder 673)
  - Munn, Norman L. (*), 1939-1947 (Box 35, Folder 674)
  - Munsell, A.H., 1911-1915 (Box 35, Folder 675)
  - Münsterberg, Hugo (*), 1898-1951 (Box 35, Folder 676-678)
  - Münsterberg, Selma (Box 35, Folder 676-678)
  - Murchison, Carl (*), 1925-1953 (Box 36, Folder 679)
    See also: box 82, folder 1583 box 97, folder 1839 box 98, folders 1844-1845 box 99, folder 1868
  - Murphy, Gardner (*), 1929-1952 (Box 36, Folder 680)
  - Myers, Charles S., 1903-1931 (Box 36, Folder 681)
  - Myers, Gilbert (*), 1949-1964 (Box 36, Folder 682)
  - Myers, Janet, 1949-1964 (Box 36, Folder 682)
  - "N" general, 1904-1955 (Box 36, Folder 683)
  - Nagel, Wilibald A., 1904-1911 (Box 36, Folder 684)
  - Neilson, William A., 1913-1938 (Box 36, Folder 685)
  - Newman, Edwin B.
    See: box 68, folders 1299-1300
  - Nicholas, John S., 1940-1956 (Box 36, Folder 686)
  - Nimkoff, N.M., 1944-1945 (Box 36, Folder 687)
  - Nissen, Henry W. (*), 1929-1937 (Box 36, Folder 688-696)
    See also: box 110, folders 2055-2063 box 111, folders 2076-2078
  - Nissen, Henry W., 1938-1947 (Box 37, Folder 697-707)
  - Nissen, Henry W., 1948-1953 (Box 38, Folder 708-710)
  - Nixdorff, Charles E. (*), 1952-1955 (Box 38, Folder 711)
  - Noback, Charles W.
    See: box 113, folders 2123-2124
  - Noble, G. Kingsley, 1938-1945 (Box 38, Folder 712)
  - Noble, Ruth (Box 38, Folder 712)
  - Noell, Mrs. Robert
    See: box 67, folders 1274-1277
  - North, Henry Ringling
    See: box 67, folder 1278
  - Norwood, Luella F. (*), 1931-1951 (Box 38, Folder 713)
  - Nowlis, Vincent (*), 1936-1946 (Box 38, Folder 714-715)
  - "O" general, 1904-1953 (Box 38, Folder 716)
  - Ogburn, William F., 1934-1942 (Box 38, Folder 717)
  - Ogden, Robert M. (*), 1915-1951 (Box 38, Folder 718)
  - Orr, P.M., 1898-1900 (Box 38, Folder 719)
  - Omwake, George L.
    See: box 91, folders 1741-1742
  - Osborn, Fairfield
    See: box 67, folders 1273 box 113
  - Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1915-1927 (Box 38, Folder 720)
  - Outhouse, Julia (*), 1931 (Box 38, Folder 721)
  - "P" general, 1900-1961, undated (Box 38, Folder 722-723)
  - Palmer, George H. (*), 1902-1933 (Box 38, Folder 724)
  - Palmer, John McAuley
    See: box 95, folder 1802
  - Panunzio, Constantine, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 725)
  - Parker, George H. (*), 1898-1955 (Box 38, Folder 726)
  - Passano, Edward B.
    See: box 62, folders 1180-1181
  - Paterson, Donald G. (*), 1930-1954 (Box 38, Folder 727)
  - Paton, Stewart (*), 1907-1942 (Box 38, Folder 728)
  - Patten, Everlin
    See: box 159, folder 2484
  - Patten, George D. (*), 1943-1947 (Box 38, Folder 729)
  - Patten, Mason
  - Paul, John R., 1943-1956 (Box 38, Folder 730)
  - Pavlov, Ivan P. (*), 1908-1950 (Box 39, Folder 731)
  - Peak, Helen (*), 1932-1956 (Box 39, Folder 732)
  - Pearce, Richard M. (*), 1926-1930 (Box 39, Folder 733)
  - Pearl, Raymond (*), 1903-1936 (Box 39, Folder 734-736)
    box 70, folders 1338-1339
    box 82, folder 1591
  - Pellens, Mildred
    See: box 60, folder 1141
  - Perry, Arthur F., Jr. (*), 1932-1946 (Box 39, Folder 737-739)
  - Perry, H. Darby (*), 1932-1946 (Box 39, Folder 737-739)
  - Perry, Dorothy (*), 1932-1946 (Box 39, Folder 737-739)
  - Perry, Doris, 1932-1946 (Box 39, Folder 737-739)
  - Perry, Bliss, 1903-1950 (Box 39, Folder 740)
  - Perry, Ralph Barton (*), 1903-1956 (Box 39, Folder 741)
  - Person, Charles W. (*), 1932-1933 (Box 39, Folder 742)
  - Peterson, Joseph
    See: box 70, folders 1347-1349, 1351 box 76, folders 1447-1448
  - Petrunkevitch, Alexander (*), 1904-1945 (Box 39, Folder 743)
  - Pfeiffer, Carroll A., 1936-1940 (Box 39, Folder 744)
  - Phillips, John C. (*), 1911-1913 (Box 39, Folder 745)
  - Pierce, George W. (*), 1910-1956 (Box 39, Folder 746)
  - Pieron, Henri, 1908-1950 (Box 39, Folder 747)
  - Pocock, R.I.
    See: box 113, folder 2117
  - Poffenberger, Albert T. (*), 1943-1956 (Box 40, Folder 748)
  - Pool, J. Lawrence (*), 1950-1960 (Box 40, Folder 749)
  - Porter, James P. (*), 1907-1916 (Box 40, Folder 750)
  - Porteus, S.D. (*), 1926-1945 (Box 40, Folder 751)
  - Prados, M., 1955 (Box 40, Folder 752)
  - Pratt, Carroll, 1943-1945 (Box 40, Folder 753)
  - Pratt, James B. (*), 1905-1917 (Box 40, Folder 754)
  - Prentiss, C.W. (*), 1902-1906 (Box 40, Folder 755)
  - Pressey, Sidney L. (*), 1916-1929 (Box 40, Folder 756-757)
  - Pribram, Karl H. (*), 1951-1956 (Box 40, Folder 758)
  - Prince, Morton, 1917-1925 (Box 40, Folder 759)
  - Pritchett, Henry S.
    See: box 80, folders 1534-1536
  - Proctor, William, 1929-1936 (Box 40, Folder 760)
  - Putman, Helen C. (*), 1916-1917 (Box 40, Folder 761)
  - Putnam, Patrick T.L., 1924 (Box 40, Folder 762)
  - "Q" general, 1953 (Box 40, Folder 763)
  - "R" general, 1899-1978 (Box 40, Folder 764-766)
  - Ramsey, Glenn V., 1943-1950 (Box 40, Folder 767)
  - Rand, Herbert W. (*), 1899-1940 (Box 40, Folder 768-774)
  - Rand, Herbert W., 1942-1961 (Box 41, Folder 775-777)
  - Reagle, John O. (*), 1898-1957 (Box 41, Folder 778)
  - Reese, Charles L. (*), 1921-1924 (Box 41, Folder 779)
  - Reichenow, Edward, 1921-1929 (Box 41, Folder 780)
  - Reno, George
    See: box 58, folder 1101
  - Revesz, Geza (*), 1923-1940 (Box 41, Folder 781)
  - Richards, Alfred N., 1944-1950 (Box 41, Folder 782)
  - Richards, Theodore W., 1912-1925 (Box 41, Folder 783)
  - Richmond, Mary E., 1927-1929 (Box 41, Folder 784)
  - Riesen, Austin H. (*), 1935-1964 (Box 41, Folder 785-786)
    See also: box 67, folder 1281, Gorilla Studies: Riesen, Austin H.
  - Ringling, John (*), 1927-1950 (Box 41, Folder 787)
  - North, John Ringling (*), 1927-1950 (Box 41, Folder 787)
  - Riopelle, Arthur J. (*), 1953-1964 (Box 41, Folder 788-790)
  - Ritter, William E. (*), 1914-1937 (Box 41, Folder 791)
    See also: box 82, folders 1593-1595
  - Roback, A.A. (*), 1916-1955 (Box 41, Folder 792)
  - Robbins, Samuel D., 1925 (Box 42, Folder 793)
  - Roberts, Helen H. (*), 1925-1954 (Box 42, Folder 794)
  - Robinson, Edward S. (*), 1922-1939 (Box 42, Folder 795)
  - Rode, M. Paul, 1935-1937 (Box 42, Folder 796)
  - Rollins, Carl P., 1941-1945 (Box 42, Folder 797)
  - Rollins, Wallace (*), 1924-1960 (Box 42, Folder 798)
  - Roofe, Paul G. (*), 1961-1965 (Box 42, Folder 799)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1934-1943 (Box 42, Folder 800)
  - Rorty, M.C., 1922-1923 (Box 42, Folder 801)
  - Rosenzwig, Saul (*), 1937-1947 (Box 42, Folder 802)
  - Rossy, Celio S. (*), 1914-1918 (Box 42, Folder 803)
  - Rothschild, Jerome J., 1945-1951 (Box 42, Folder 804)
  - Rouse, John E. (*), 1904-1915 (Box 42, Folder 805)
  - Royce, Josiah (*), 1903-1917 (Box 42, Folder 806)
  - Rowe, Allen W., 1932-1934 (Box 42, Folder 807)
  - Ruch, Theodore C., 1937-1950 (Box 42, Folder 808)
  - Rugg, Harold O., 1921-1922 (Box 42, Folder 809)
  - Rugg Report (Box 42, Folder 809)
  - Ruggles, Arthur H. (*), 1925-1941 (Box 42, Folder 810)
  - Ruml, Beardsley, 1924-1949 (Box 42, Folder 811)
    See also: box 88, folders 1693-1694
  - Russell, Constance (*), 1950-1955 (Box 42, Folder 812)
  - Russell, Lee (*), 1920-1947 (Box 42, Folder 813-814)
  - Russell, Lewis H.
    See: box 158, folders 2477-2479
  - "S" general, 1899-1956 (Box 42, Folder 815-817)
  - Salmon, Thomas W. (*), 1916-1952 (Box 43, Folder 818)
  - Sanford, Edmund C., 1899-1924 (Box 43, Folder 819)
    See also: box 60, folder 1138
  - Sanford, Fillmore H. (*), 1950-1956 (Box 43, Folder 820)
  - Sapir, Edward (*), 1934-1939 (Box 43, Folder 821)
  - Sargent, Porter (*), 1937-1951 (Box 43, Folder 122)
  - Sarris, E.G., 1932-1937 (Box 43, Folder 823)
  - Sawyer, Majorie H., 1914-1916 (Box 43, Folder 824)
  - Scheinfeld, Amram (*), 1943-1953 (Box 43, Folder 825)
  - Schneirla, Theodore C. (*), 1943-1954 (Box 43, Folder 826)
  - Schram, Jacob R., 1923-1965 (Box 43, Folder 827)
  - Schultz, Adolph H. (*), 1927-1950 (Box 43, Folder 828-829)
  - Schwidetzky, Georg W.A. (*), 1932-1952 (Box 43, Folder 830)
  - Scott, John P. (*), 1942-1954 (Box 43, Folder 831)
    See also: box 70, folders 1334-1337
  - Scott, Walter Dill, 1919-1949 (Box 43, Folder 832)
  - Scripps, Edward W. (*), 1915-1926 (Box 43, Folder 833-834)
  - Sears, Robert R. (*), 1934-1957 (Box 43, Folder 835)
  - Seashore, Carl E. (*), 1910-1950 (Box 43, Folder 836-837)
  - Sedgwick, Ellery
    See: box 82, folder 1579
  - Selenka, Margaretha, 1916 (Box 44, Folder 838)
  - Sellheim, Alexandre P. (*), 1929-1961 (Box 44, Folder 839)
  - Seton, Ernest Thompson, 1900-1946 (Box 44, Folder 840)
  - Seward, John P., 1937-1946 (Box 44, Folder 841)
  - Seward, Georgene H. (*) (Box 44, Folder 841)
  - Seymour, Charles
    See: box 105, folder 1973
  - Shapley, Harlow (*), 1945-1948 (Box 44, Folder 842)
  - Shaw, Henry A. (*), 1918-1931 (Box 44, Folder 843)
  - Sherrington, Charles S. (*), 1904-1952 (Box 44, Folder 844)
  - Shull, George H. (*), 1917-1919 (Box 44, Folder 845)
  - Sills, Kenneth C.M., 1945 (Box 44, Folder 846)
  - Silver, Edwin H., 1946-1953 (Box 44, Folder 847)
  - Simmons, Will, 1925-1927 (Box 44, Folder 848)
  - Sinnot, Edmund W. (*), 1948-1955 (Box 44, Folder 849)
  - Sisson, Edward O., 1943-1945 (Box 44, Folder 850)
  - Skinner, Burrhus F., 1945-1954 (Box 44, Folder 851)
  - Smith, Gertrude M. (*), 1916-1918 (Box 44, Folder 852-853)
  - Smith, Homer W. (*), 1932-1953 (Box 44, Folder 854)
  - Smith, Meredith (*), 1949-1953 (Box 44, Folder 855)
  - Smith, Phillip E. (*), 1939 (Box 44, Folder 856)
  - Smith, Theobald
    See: box 106, folder 2005
  - Smith, William A. (*), 1927-1929 (Box 44, Folder 857)
  - Solomon, Henry C. (*), 1915-1947 (Box 44, Folder 858)
  - Sontag, Lester W.
    See: box 64, folders 1208-1218
  - Southard, Elmer Ernest (*), 1912-1921 (Box 44, Folder 859-860)
  - Spaeth, Edith T. (*), 1925-1927 (Box 44, Folder 861)
  - Spangler, Ralph H. (*), 1905-1956 (Box 44, Folder 862)
    See also: box 91, folders 1739-1740
  - Sparks, Richard D. (*), 1925-1938 (Box 44, Folder 863-864)
    See also: box 68, folder 1285
  - Spence, Kenneth W. (*), 1929-1933 (Box 44, Folder 865-866)
  - Spence, Kenneth W., 1934-1956 (Box 45, Folder 867-872)
  - Spencer, C. Sidney (*), 1924-1925 (Box 45, Folder 873)
  - Speranza, Gino (*), 1924-1928 (Box 45, Folder 874-875)
  - Spragg, S.D. Shirley (*), 1933-1952 (Box 45, Folder 876-878)
  - Starch, Daniel, 1938, 1941 (Box 45, Folder 879)
  - Stearns, Myron W. (*), 1947-1948 (Box 45, Folder 880)
  - Stevens, Emily (*), 1949-1955 (Box 45, Folder 881)
  - Stevens, S. Smith, 1946-1952 (Box 45, Folder 882)
  - Stewart, George R., 1946 (Box 45, Folder 883)
  - Stewart, George W. (*), 1921-1952 (Box 45, Folder 884)
  - Stiles, Charles W., 1926-1927 (Box 45, Folder 885)
  - Stockard, Charles R. (*), 1931-1939 (Box 45, Folder 886)
  - Stone, Calvin P. (*), 1922-1956 (Box 45, Folder 887)
  - Stone, James H. (*), 1942-1956 (Box 45, Folder 888)
  - Storey, T.A.
    See: box 60, folder 1150
  - Stowell, Geraldine (*), 1923-1932 (Box 46, Folder 889)
  - Strassburg, Ed C.
    See: box 60, folder 1136
  - Stratton, George M.
    See: box 74, folders 1401-1403
  - Streeter, George L. (*), 1923-1940 (Box 46, Folder 890)
  - Strong, R. Myron (*), 1900-1960 (Box 46, Folder 891-894)
  - Stuart, Harold C.
  - Sulloway, Richard (*), 1935-1956 (Box 46, Folder 895)
  - Summer, Francis B. (*), 1905-1954 (Box 46, Folder 896)
  - "T" general, 1899-1981 (Box 46, Folder 897-898)
  - Tait, William D. (*), 1912-1935 (Box 46, Folder 899)
  - Taliaferro, William H. (*), 1939-1956 (Box 46, Folder 900)
  - Tausig, F.W. (*), 1899-1940 (Box 46, Folder 901)
  - Taylor, Franklin V., 1935 (Box 46, Folder 902)
  - Taylor, Henry Osborn (*), 1925-1938 (Box 46, Folder 903)
  - Taylor, Howard E. (*), 1900-1956 (Box 46, Folder 904)
  - Taylor, Marshall, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 905)
  - Taylor, William S.
    See: box 97, folder 1842
  - Tembrock, Günter (*), 1949-1952 (Box 46, Folder 906)
  - Terman, Lewis M. (*), 1915-1947 (Box 46, Folder 907-911)
  - Terman, Lewis M., 1948-1957 (Box 47, Folder 912-915)
  - Thomas, Charles C.
    See: box 62, folders 1184-1185 box 84, folders 1635-1636
  - Thomas, Edward E., 1945-1947 (Box 47, Folder 916)
  - Thompson, Charles E.
  - Thompson, Helen (*), 1930-1955 (Box 47, Folder 917)
  - Thornburg, S. Raymond, 1937-1948 (Box 47, Folder 918)
  - Thorndike, Edward L. (*), 1899-1972 (Box 47, Folder 919-920)
    See also: box 60, folder 1138 box 71, folder 1368
  - Thorne, Frederick C., 1944-1945 (Box 47, Folder 921)
  - Thurnwald, Richard C., 1932 (Box 47, Folder 922)
  - Thurstone, Louis L. (*), 1922-1955 (Box 47, Folder 923)
  - Tilney, Frederick (*), 1928-1936 (Box 47, Folder 924)
  - Tinbergen, Niko (*), 1938-1947 (Box 47, Folder 925)
  - Tinklepaugh, Otto L. (*), 1926-1930 (Box 47, Folder 926)
  - Tinklepaugh, Otto L., 1930-1943 (Box 48, Folder 927-932)
  - Titchener, E.B. (*), 1905-1927 (Box 48, Folder 933-935)
    See also: box 91, folder 1738 box 178, folder 2692
  - Todd, T. Wingate (*), 1929-1939 (Box 48, Folder 936-937)
    See also: box 61, folder 1153
  - Toll, Charles H. (*), 1908-1915 (Box 49, Folder 938)
  - Toll, Henry W.
    See: box 80, folder 1521
  - Tolman, Edward C. (*), 1917-1953 (Box 49, Folder 939)
  - Tolstoy, Alexandra L., 1934-1939 (Box 49, Folder 940)
  - Tomilin, Michael I. (*), 1931-1938 (Box 49, Folder 941-943)
  - Tower, Ralph W., 1925-1927 (Box 49, Folder 944)
  - Troland, Leonard T., 1916-1928 (Box 49, Folder 945)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1945-1958 (Box 49, Folder 946)
  - "U" general, 1917-1945 (Box 49, Folder 947)
  - Uexküll, Baron Jacob von, 1934 (Box 49, Folder 948)
  - Uhrbrock, Richard S. (*), 1933-1955 (Box 49, Folder 949)
  - Upton, Morgan, 1927-1928 (Box 49, Folder 950)
  - Urban, F.M. (*), 1910-1952 (Box 49, Folder 951)
  - Urban, Wilbur M., 1930-1931 (Box 49, Folder 952)
  - "V" general, 1899-1951 (Box 49, Folder 953)
  - Valentine, Willard L., 1944-1946 (Box 49, Folder 954)
  - Vance, Williams R. (*), 1925-1940, undated (Box 49, Folder 955)
  - Van de Water, Marjorie
    See: box 83, folders 1597-1598
  - Van den Berghe, Louis (*), 1948-1950 (Box 49, Folder 956)
  - Van Wagenen, Bleecker, 1912-1913 (Box 49, Folder 957)
  - Vaughan, Victor C., 1921-1929 (Box 49, Folder 958)
  - Vincent, George E. (*), 1926-1940 (Box 49, Folder 959)
  - Visscher, Maurice B., 1944-1957 (Box 49, Folder 960)
  - "W" general, 1899-1955 (Box 49, Folder 961-963)
  - Wallace, Henry A. (*), 1936-1947 (Box 50, Folder 964)
  - Wallace, Robert B., 1936-1947 (Box 50, Folder 964)
  - Ward, Egbert H.P., 1947 (Box 50, Folder 965)
  - Warden, Carl J. (*), 1927-1945 (Box 50, Folder 966)
  - Warner, Lucien H. (*), 1927-1939 (Box 50, Folder 967)
  - Warren, Howard C. (*), 1910-1931 (Box 50, Folder 968-970)
    See also: box 89, folder 1711
  - Washburn, Margaret F. (*), 1907-1950 (Box 50, Folder 971-973)
  - Watson, John B. (*), 1904-1911 (Box 50, Folder 974-981)
  - Watson, John B., 1911-1933 (Box 51, Folder 982-988)
    See also: box 86, folders 1671-1672 box 87-88, folders 1688-1692
  - Waugh, Karl, 1907-1932 (Box 51, Folder 989)
  - Way, Mary S.
    See: box 68, folder 1292
  - Weaver, Warren (*), 1935-1954 (Box 51, Folder 990)
  - Weed, Lewis H.
    See: box 69, folder 1313
  - Weinert, Hans, 1932-1933 (Box 51, Folder 991)
  - Weiss, Paul, 1942-1954 (Box 51, Folder 992)
    See also: box 55, folder 1053
  - Welch, William H. (*), 1916-1935 (Box 51, Folder 993)
  - Wells, F. Lyman (*), 1916-1940 (Box 51, Folder 994)
  - Wells, France, 1937 (Box 51, Folder 995)
  - Wells, H. Gideon (*), 1923-1942 (Box 51, Folder 996)
    See also: box 106, folder 2006
  - Werner, Heinz
    See: box 57, folders 1077-1082
  - Wessel, Bessie B. (*), 1925-1927 (Box 51, Folder 997)
  - Wever, Ernest G. (*), 1930-1931 (Box 51, Folder 998)
  - Wheeler, William M. (*), 1908-1937 (Box 51, Folder 999)
  - Whipple, Guy M. (*), 1910-1916 (Box 51, Folder 1000)
  - White, David
    See: box 71, folders 1368-1369
  - Whiting, Charles F. (*), 1912-1975 (Box 52, Folder 1001-1005)
  - Whiting, Isabel K. (Box 52, Folder 1001-1005)
  - Whitman, Charles O., 1899-1911 (Box 52, Folder 1006)
  - Whitney, Leon F. (*), 1925-1957 (Box 52, Folder 1007)
    See also: box 80, folders 1518-1520
  - Wiggam, A.E.
    See: box 100, folder 1880
  - Williams, Frankwood E.
    See: box 81, folders 1552-1554 box 81, folders 1555-1556
  - Williams, Greer (*), 1947-1949 (Box 52, Folder 1008)
  - Williams, Roger J. (*), 1946-1950 (Box 52, Folder 1009)
  - Williams, Stephen R., 1899-1940 (Box 52, Folder 1010)
  - Wilson, Edwin B., 1934, 1942 (Box 52, Folder 1011)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1917-1921 (Box 52, Folder 1012)
  - Wing, Kempton G., 1940-1941 (Box 52, Folder 1013)
  - Winternitz, Milton C. (*), 1927-1950 (Box 52, Folder 1014)
    See also: box 103, folders 1941-1944 box 105, folders 1982-1984
  - Wislocki, George B. (*), 1931-1952 (Box 52, Folder 1015)
  - Wissler, Clark (*), 1921-1947 (Box 52, Folder 1016)
    See also: box 74, folders 1401-1403 box 106, folder 2007
  - Witschi, Emil, 1938-1947 (Box 52, Folder 1017)
  - Witt, Barbara J. (*), 1948 (Box 52, Folder 1018)
  - Wolfard, Edith L., 1912-1915 (Box 52, Folder 1019)
  - Wolfe, John B. (*), 1932-1940 (Box 52, Folder 1020)
  - Wolfle, Dael L. (*), 1944-1955 (Box 53, Folder 1021)
  - Woodrow, Herbert H.
    See: box 70, folders 1347-1350
  - Woodruff, Lorande L., 1939 (Box 53, Folder 1022)
  - Woods, Archie S.
    See: box 69, folder 1312
  - Woods, Arthur, 1915, 1928 (Box 53, Folder 1023)
  - Woods, James H., 1914-1924 (Box 53, Folder 1024)
  - Woodward, Robert S.
  - Woodworth, Robert S., 1911-1954 (Box 53, Folder 1025)
    See also: box 69, folder 1312
  - Woodyatt, Rollin, 1901-1904 (Box 53, Folder 1026)
  - Woolley, Helen T. (*), 1916-1925 (Box 53, Folder 1027)
  - Woolston, Howard B. (*), 1902-1916 (Box 53, Folder 1028)
  - "X,Y,Z" general (Box 53, Folder 1029)
  - Yoakum, Clarence S. (*), 1917-1945 (Box 53, Folder 1030)
  - Yoshioka, Joseph G. (*), 1929-1943 (Box 53, Folder 1031-1033)
  - Young, Donald, 1947-1955 (Box 53, Folder 1034)
  - Young, Paul T. (*), 1939-1945 (Box 53, Folder 1035)
  - Young, William C. (*), 1935-1941 (Box 53, Folder 1036-1039)
  - Young, William C., 1942-1965 (Box 54, Folder 1040-1041)
  - Zänkart, Adolph (*), 1950-1952 (Box 54, Folder 1042)
  - Zinn, Earl F. (*), 1921-1951 (Box 54, Folder 1043)
    See also: box 77-78, folders 1468-1474
  - Zuckerman, Solly (*), 1932-1957 (Box 54, Folder 1044-1046)
- Subject Files, 1893-1967; Series II; 24.5 linear feet (59 boxes)
  Series II, SUBJECT FILES, consists primarily of correspondence, but it also includes reports, minutes of meetings, and other papers. The material is arranged alphabetically by broad subject area, from American Academy of Arts and Sciences to Zoos.
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1915-1952 (Box 55, Folder 1047)
    - Commission to Study the Academy, 1944-1947 (Box 55, Folder 1048-1049)
  - American Association for Applied Psychology, 1938-1945 (Box 55, Folder 1050)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1915-1948 (Box 55, Folder 1051-1052)
    - Committee on Scientific Policy, 1946-1947 (Box 55, Folder 1053)
    - Executive Committee, Section 1, 1945-1951 (Box 55, Folder 1054)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1936-1954 (Box 55, Folder 1055-1056)
    - Committee on Publications, 1951-1954 (Box 55, Folder 1057-1059)
  - American Psychological Association, 1910-1954 (Box 56, Folder 1060-1067)
    - Committee on Standardization of Psychological Procedure, 1915-1917 (Box 56, Folder 1068-1069)
    - Committee on Incorporation, 1923-1925 (Box 56, Folder 1070)
    - Committee on Relation of Psychology to Public Welfare, 1923-1925 (Box 56, Folder 1071)
    - Committee on Animal Experimentation, 1925-1932 (Box 56, Folder 1072-1073)
    - Appointment of Emergency Committee, 1939-1940 (Box 56, Folder 1074)
    - Professional Training in Psychology, 1941 (Box 56, Folder 1075)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1954 (Box 56, Folder 1076)
    - Committee on History of Psychology in Autobiography, Vol. IV, 1949-1952 (Box 57, Folder 1077-1082)
    - Committee on International Relations in Psychology, 1952-1953 (Box 57, Folder 1083)
  - Animal Colony: Dealers
    - Miscellaneous, 1913-1937 (Box 57, Folder 1084)
    - Breeding and Laboratory Institute, 1932-1937 (Box 57, Folder 1085)
    - J.L. Buck, 1925-1936 (Box 57, Folder 1086-1087)
  - Anthropoid Research
    - Plan for Study of the Anthropoid Apes, 1913-1916 (Box 57, Folder 1088)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1913-1935 (Box 57, Folder 1089)
    - Canary Islands, 1913-1921 (Box 57, Folder 1090)
    - Santa Barbara, California, 1914-1915 (Box 57, Folder 1091)
    - Chim and Panzee expenses, 1923-1925 (Box 57, Folder 1092)
    - Apparatus, equipment, supplies, etc., 1923-1925 (Box 57, Folder 1093)
    - Rockefeller grant in Institute of Psychology, 1925-1929 (Box 57, Folder 1094)
    - Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, 1929-1942 (Box 57, Folder 1095)
    - Reservations for Europe and Africa, 1929 (Box 57, Folder 1096)
    - Apparatus, equipment, supplies, housing, 1926-1931 (Box 58, Folder 1097-1098)
    - Cuban Expedition
      - Finances, 1924-1928 (Box 58, Folder 1099)
      - Reports, 1924-1929 (Box 58, Folder 1100)
      - Miscellaneous, 1924-1925 (Box 58, Folder 1101)